你一个人在这等能行吗
Think you'll be okay waiting here by yourself?
恩  不用管我
Yeah. Whatever.
先生  如果您要吸烟
Uh, sir, if you'd like to smoke,
请到远离大门20英尺的地方抽
you need to be another 20 feet from the door.
那你不知道把我推远点吗  贱人
So roll me further, bitch.
病人什么情况
What's coming?
男  白人
Male Caucasian.
四十来岁
Early 40s.
多处枪伤
Multiple gunshot wounds.
血压70
BP is 70. 7-0 over palp.
脉搏140
Pulse 140-- 1-4-0.
手臂脉搏微弱
Weak and thready at the brachial.
右肺无呼吸迹象
No breath sounds on the right side,
腹部僵硬
and the belly is rigid.
病人面部无血色并伴有严重出汗
Patient appears pale and diaphoretic.
有几处伤口
How many entry wounds?
发现四处   肩部和臀部  穿透伤
We found four-- shoulder and hip, through and through.
右肺还有左下肺
Right lung and lower left quadrant,
无可见致命伤
no visible exit wounds.
给他2克氧气
Let's give him 2 grams of oxygen.
-血红蛋白指数多少  -7.3
- What's his hemoglobin? - 7.3.
我需要2个大号针头给他挂点滴
I need two large-bore IVs,
6单位O型血  阴性
6 units O-neg,
交叉血型还需要6单位
type and cross for 6 more units,
做个胸透和腹部平片
Chest X-ray and KUB.
通知手术室  我们马上就到
Notify the O.R. We are on the way.
一号手术室可以使用  把他抬进去
O.R. One is clear. Let's put him in there.
杰西  不好意思  哥们  我迟到了
Yo, Jesse, sorry I'm late, man.
靠  哥们  瞧瞧你自己
Damn, brother, look at you.
简直一团糟
That's messed up.
感觉怎样  还好吗
How are you feeling? You okay?
老实说
Actually...
我感觉好极了
I'm great.
绝
命
毒
师
第三季
第八集
我不明白
I don't understand.
我还以为一切进展顺利呢
I thought things were going pretty well.
我...
I--
我还以为我们相处得很融洽
I thought we were kind of simpatico,
知道吗
you know?
我还以为我们会成为真正的团队
We were becoming a real team.
不是  不是你想得这么好
Uh, not-- not so much, no.
是因为那天的温度设定的问题吗
Is this about the temperature setting the other day?
我向你保证绝对不会再发生此类情况...
Because I can assure you that will not happen--
不仅仅是因为那个原因  盖尔
No, it's bigger than that, Gale.
原因...要比那个严重得多
It's-- It's-- It's much more than that.
能说详细点吗
Could you elaborate?
当然  当然可以详细点
Well, uh, yes, of course I could,
但我认为这种
but I don't think either of us
长期的合作关系  对我们彼此都不太有益...
would necessarily benefit from a prolonged...
恩  就是这样
uh, yeah, so...
没错
yeah.
整间实验室都是我装配的
I set up the entire lab.
你不是说你喜欢这配置吗
You said you liked the configuration.
我的确喜欢
And I do.
至少大部分喜欢
For the most part.
你真的是一个很优秀的化学家
Look, you're a fine chemist, really,
前途一片光明
with a promising future.
只是...我...
It's just that-- that I--
我们有点...
that-- that we just have different...
不合拍  盖尔
rhythms, Gale.
就好比是...
It's-- It's--
就好比  我是古典音乐
It's as if I'm classical
而你却更像是
but you are-- are more...
爵士乐
jazz.
-爵士乐  -爵士乐
- Jazz. - Jazz.
对
Yes.
当然  爵士乐绝没有任何不对的地方
And God knows there is nothing wrong with jazz.
只不过  我需要的是...
It's simply that I require--
古典音乐
Classical.
完全正确
Exactly.
我操
Oh, shit.
哥们  这地方太牛了
Man, this is the bomb.
你好啊  合伙人
What's up, partner?
-难以置信  -这就是来代替我的吗
- I can't believe this. - This is my replacement?
我的天
Oh, Jesus.
你好  我是盖尔  见到你很高兴
Hi. Gale. Nice to meet you.
你好
What's up?
靠  我们早就该在几月前把那房车扔了
Damn, we should have ditched that RV months ago.
这里简直让人眼前一亮
It's all, like, shining up in here.
不好意思  是不是还有什么没告诉我的
I'm sorry. I must be missing something.
我不是...不是故意要...
I don't mean-- I don't mean to be--
-这  -我的天
- This-- - No!
这完全没道理
...makes no sense.
那么...
So...
我想我们应该...
I guess this is--
我的老天爷
Oh, dear mother of God.
这完全是为了大局着想
This is for the best.
一周交200磅的货
200 pounds a week.
懂吗
Got it?
我的天
Oh, man! Oh!
怀特老师
Mr. White!
好了  有很多东西需要给你展示
Okay. There's a lot to show you.
还有些新技术你要学的
Some new techniques to learn.
现在吗
What, now?
对  现在
Yes, now.
还有几天时间就要交下一批货了
We've only got a couple of days before our next batch is due,
我得让你跟上进度
and I need to get you up to speed.
很好
Right on.
我只是想问...
I'm just saying--
这下面的手机信号好不好
How's the cell service down here?
根本就没信号
It's nonexistent.
这里是隔离了的
We're shielded.
有条紧急线路  来吧
There's a hard line for emergencies. Come on.
这么说你还没和其他人说过话吧
So you haven't talked to anybody today
当然  那位科学呆子老兄除外
other than, you know, Captain Nerd there.
怎么了
Why?
你那连襟
Your brother-in-law.
他怎么了
What about him?
-什么情况  -刚送来  毫无反应
- So what's the story? - Upon arrival, he was unresponsive.
你来看一下  把伤口再暴露一点
Take a look. You getting some exposure on those wounds?
血压80
...blood pressure of 80.
2单位的生理盐水
2 units of normal saline.
情况很糟
We've got a bivalve mass.
他呼吸声很急促
He's got breath sounds bilaterally.
这根大腿骨似乎全碎了
This femur feels like a wet bag of gravel.
另外一根也没好到哪去
The other one's not much better.
鞋子给他脱掉
Let's get those boots off.
看看有无脉搏
See if you get a pulse.
测个血压  或是做个踝肱指数检测
You get a blood pressure cup or an ABI?
血浆来没有
Where's that blood?
先生  有什么事吗
Sir, can I help you?
是的  我...
Uh, yeah, I--
没事的  他是病人家属
It's all right. He's family.
谢谢
Thank you.
玛丽
Marie.
别担心  别着急
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
我也很难过
I'm so sorry.
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
他怎么样了
How is he?
不知道  他们不愿意透露
I don't know. They won't really tell us anything.
他还在手术中
He's still in surgery.
他身中四枪
They shot him four times.
上帝啊
Oh, Chirst.
霍莉呢
Where's Holly?
我找了个临时保姆
I got a sitter.
你还好吗
Hey. How are you, huh?
-还不错  -是吗
- Fine. - Yeah?
你确定
Sure?
我没事  只是需要透透气
I-- I'm fine. I just need some fresh air.
好吧
Okay.
让我来开门吧
Here. Let me get the door.
我自己来  我没事
I got it. I'm fine.
沃尔特  对吧
Walt. Hmm?
沃尔特  这位是特别探员马科特
Walt, this is ASAC Merkert.
沃尔特是汉克的连襟
Hank's brother-in-law Walt.
你好
Hello.
我深表遗憾
I'm very sorry.
谢谢你
Thank you. Uh--
能告诉我们事发经过吗
Can you tell us anything or any details?
只知道汉克中了那两人的埋伏
Right now, all we know is two men ambushed Hank.
没有他们的身份记录
They didn't have any I.D. On them.
可能是墨西哥侨民
Probably Mexican nationals.
纹身显示其与贩毒集团有瓜葛
Their tattoos indicated an affiliation with the drug cartel.
他们为什么要袭击汉克
Why did they attack Hank?
目前还不清楚
We're not sure yet.
可能与汉克正在调查的案子有关
It could be in relation to an investigation that Hank was working,
也可能是向缉毒局示威
or it could be a message to the DEA in general.
他们手持斧头
They had an ax.
这个犯罪集团想要引人注目
The cartels tend to be dramatic.
我的天
Oh, Jesus.
他们在哪里  我是说...
Where are they? I mean, did they--
汉克把他们都放倒了
Hank got both of them.
击毙了一个
He killed one outright,
另一个在楼上  在抢救
and the other one's upstairs in critical condition.
你连襟这小子是硬汉
Your brother-in-law's one tough son of a b----
能干掉两个
to take them both out,
而且没有配枪
considering he didn't even have his gun.
他没有配枪吗
He didn't have his gun?
为什么汉克没有配枪
Why didn't Hank have his gun?
玛丽  打人案件
Marie, the assault charge.
调查期间不得已暂停汉克的职务
I had to suspend Hank pending the investigation.
也就是说我没收了他的配枪
That means I had to take away his weapon.
这是标准程序  没有人...
It's standard procedure. No one--
好了  给我听好了
Okay, All right. Listen.
如果你们一开始
If you would have all listened to him
就听他的
right from the start,
让他去抓那个小混混
and let him arrest that little degenerate,
他也不至于如此被动
he wouldn't have had to take things into his own hands,
有配枪他就能保护自己
and he would have had a gun and defended himself.
玛丽  让我们...
Marie, let's just--
别  让我...
No. Just--
这都是他们的错
It's their fault.
他没有配枪
He didn't have a gun.
亲爱的  这无济于事
Honey, this isn't helping you.
你
You.
你算是什么搭档
What kind of partner are you?
你应该支援他的
You were supposed to back him up,
可你在哪里
and where were you?
那时候你在哪里
Where were you?
德州
Texas.
还有你
And you.
你应该保护你的探员
You're supposed to protect your agents
而你却没收他们的配枪
instead of taking their guns,
不支持他们
not supporting them,
不支援他们...
not backing them up--
-玛丽  -当他们...
- Marie. Marie. - ...when they--
亲爱的  过去坐下好吗
Honey, let's just go and sit down, okay?
在他们给我滚出去之前  我哪里也不去
I'm not doing anything until these two get the hell out of here.
我是认真的
I mean it.
-非常抱歉  -走
- Sorry-- - Go.
这里不欢迎你们
You are not welcome here.
这里不欢迎缉毒局的人
The DEA is not welcome here.
亲爱的
Honey.
来吧
Come on.
过来坐下
Come on. Let's go sit down.
不只是他们
It's not just them.
还有你  沃尔特
It's you, Walt.
汉克在找的这个平克曼
This Pinkman that Hank was looking for--
如果不是你从他那买大麻
Hank would have never even heard his name
他根本不会知道有这个人
if you hadn't bought marijuana from him.
玛丽
Marie--
你有想过吗  沃尔特
Do you ever think about that, Walt?
想过吗
Do you?
你有想过他这一切都是拜你所赐吗
Do you ever think about everything that you have put him through?
玛丽  别说了
Marie, stop.
你心烦
You're upset,
想找人发泄
and you're looking for someone to blame,
我可以理解  但不能怪沃尔特
and it's understandable, but don't blame Walt.
不是他的错
It's not his fault.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
亲爱的  别  不要...
Sweetheart. No. No. No. Don't--
没事的
It's okay.
汉克他...
It's Hank--
没事的
It's all right.
好了  可以了
All right, you're done.
下一位
Okay, next.
有人吗
Hello!
有人吗  吗  吗  吗...
Hello, hello, hello, hello, hello.
杰西·平克曼登场了
Jesse Pinkman in the house!
我的天
Oh, my dear God.
沃尔特·怀特  有你的电话
Walter White to the nearest courtesy phone.
Walter White, please pick up a courtesy phone.
我们几时开工
Yo. We working sometime this year?
你到底在想什么
What the hell are you thinking?
为什么打到这里来
Why are you calling me here?
打你手机  直接转到了语音信箱
I tried your cell, and it went straight to voice mail.
我还能怎么联系你
How else am I supposed to get hold of you?
不要联系我
You aren't.
都一整天了
Look, man, it's been a whole day.
还得要悲伤多久
How long is this grieving process?
干脆让我打卡下班算了
Just put a clock on it for me.
我只想说我们得按计划行事  对吧
All's I'm saying is we have a schedule, right?
我的家人比你的计划重要
My family comes before your schedule.
老兄  这可不是我的计划
Dude, it's not my schedule.
我们在此是有任务在身的
We have responsibilities here.
我心里有数
I'll get there when I get there.
随你便
You know what? Whatever.
我自己制毒
I'll just cook on my own.
不行
You will do no such thing.
为什么不行
Why not?
作为新手
Well, uh, for starters,
你根本不懂怎么操作那些设备
you aren't the least bit familiar with any of the equipment.
总有说明书之类的吧
There's got to be some sort of manual, right?
我认识字
And I can read.
杰西  什么都别碰
Jesse, touch nothing.
行了  别把我当助手那样使唤
Yo, stop treating me I'm like your assistant.
我可不听你发号施令
I'm not your bitch to order around.
我们是合伙人关系
We're partners.
知道吗
Remember?
坐着耐心地等我
I need you to sit patiently and wait,
我会尽快赶到
and I will be there as soon as I can.
谢谢你的关心
Thank you very much for your kind words.
我们...非常感谢
We-- We really do appreciate that.
怎么   你妻子在旁边
What, is your wife there?
是的  她在
Uh, yes. Yes, she is,
而且她会很高兴你能打电话来问候
and she would be happy to know that you asked about her.
保持联络
And please do keep us in your thoughts.
告诉你那混蛋连襟
Hey, tell your douche-bag brother-in-law
早点超度算了
to head towards the light.
我在想
So I'm thinking, um,
不如大家一起去吃个早饭
maybe we should go get everybody some breakfast.
好啊  主意不错
Yeah. That sounds good.
知道刚才是谁吗
Do you know who that was?
我说  煎蛋还不错
You know, these eggs are really not too bad.
你们看
Look at that.
看什么
Look at what?
看什么  看这个  叉子上的斑点
At what? This. These spots.
这叉子明显是脏的
This fork is absolutely filthy.
你看到了吧
Tell me you see this.
你眼神好  看看这个
You've got good eyes. Look at that.
玛丽  只不过是水渍而已
Marie, those are just water spots.
叉子没问题
Fork is fine.
才不是水渍
Those are not water spots.
明明是脏的
That's dirt.
这餐具明显没洗过
This silverware's obviously not been cleaned.
满是别人口腔里的病菌
It's covered in germs from someone else's mouth.
天知道什么鬼东西
God knows what.
玛丽阿姨  真的是水渍
Seriously, Aunt Marie, it's water spots.
我们家里的叉子也不比这干净
Ours at home aren't any better.
这跟你们家的叉子无关
Yours at home are irrelevant.
我们这是在医院里
We're in a hospital.
医院的卫生水平应该更高
They need to be held to a higher standard.
这是他们的职责
They have a responsibility.
我不确定
Well, I'm not actually sure
这间自助餐厅是否可以算是
if the cafeteria necessarily qualifies
医院的一部分
as being part of a hospital.
它就在医院的大楼里
It's in the same building.
同一个屋檐下
It's all under the same roof.
病人们吃饭用的
Do you think that sick people aren't eating
不也是这沾染了细菌的餐具吗
with this bacteria-infected silverware?
上帝啊  病从口入  叫人怎么活
My God, how are you supposed to survive this death trap?
玛丽
Marie.
我不是活过来了吗
I survived.
我在这家医院做的肿瘤切除手术
I had my lumpectomy at this hospital.
记得吗
Remember that?
还记得当时我们有多害怕吗
Remember how scared we all were?
我不想表现出来而已
I didn't want to act like it,
可我真的吓坏了
but I was terrified.
整整一周  我脑子里想的都是
All that week, all I could think of was
他们会怎么把我的身体切开
how they were actually going to cut me open
把我与生俱来的一部分从体内取走
and take out a part of me that was with me my entire life.
这个念头挥之不去
I couldn't get that image out of my head.
我觉得最可怕的就是
I think the scariest part was when...
做手术准备的时候
they took me into pre-op,
躺在那里
lying there,
等着被麻醉
waiting for them to anesthetize you,
心里清楚
knowing that...
自己可能再也醒不过来了
you may never wake up again.
事实上
Actually,
我还记得那天开车来医院的时候
what I really remember about that day is driving to the hospital.
斯凯勒  记得吗  那天我要自己开车
Skyler, you remember me wanting to drive that day?
记得
Yeah.
反正  那天我们开车走中央公路的时候
Anyway, there we are. We're driving up Central,
每个路口都是绿灯
and we hit every green light...
我是说每个经过的路口
I mean, every single light that we hit...
都是绿灯
sheew... green.
这是什么概率
When does that happen?
就是  梆 梆
Just like bang, bang,
一路绿灯
green the entire way.
一路上  我一直都在想
And the whole time, all I could think about was
"为什么偏偏是今天  为什么"
"Why today? Why?
"为什么不能让我和家人"
"Why can't I just spend a few extra minutes
"在车里多坐一会儿"
"in the car with my family?"
我这辈子从没那么盼过堵车
I never wanted to be stuck in traffic so bad in my life.
至少那时我和家人在一起
At least I was with my family.
有家人支持
I had that.
不管怎么说  我活过来了
Anyway, I survived this place.
你丈夫比我强壮得多
And I'm not half the man your husband is.
你好
Yes?
你那边到底怎么回事
我正要问你呢
I was going to ask you the same question.
知道我的人出事了吗
听说他们袭击一名缉毒局探员
I heard they they attacked a DEA agent.
怎么回事  不会说西班牙语了吗
不是我下的命令
I didn't order this,
我的手下也不会擅自行事
and my men would never do this on their own.
一定是有人指使的
Someone gave the go-ahead.
你是在指责我吗
Are you accusing me?
我只是说他们不会自行其是
I'm just saying they wouldn't act on their own.
我也没有自取灭亡的习惯
I am not in the habit of picking my own pocket.
我估计下批到货要推迟了吧
I assume that the next shipment will be delayed.
货大概多久能到
Any thoughts on when it might arrive?
一周  或许一个月
A week, a month.
现在边境查得太严
There's too much focus on the border.
我们眼下需要暂时低调
We lay low for the time being.
低调行事
We lay low,
然后等活下来的那个  告诉我真相
and then we get the real story from my man who survived.
你的人被拘禁了
Your man is in custody.
上帝保佑美国
在宣判之前他都是无罪的
He's innocent until proven guilty.
不是吗
Correct?
我会给他请最好的律师
I'll get him the best lawyer,
然后会真相大白的
and then we'll learn the truth.
有消息随时通知我
Well, keep me apprised.
任何靠近脊柱的外伤
Any time you've got that close proximity to the spine,
都是需要谨慎对待的
there's always going to be cause for concern,
但我也说了
but, as I say,
现在下结论为时尚早
it's really too soon to tell.
至少他出了手术室  这算是...
He's out of surgery, at least, which is...
离开手术室  正被送往恢复室
Out of surgery, on his way to recovery.
好  恢复室在哪儿
All right. Where's that?
对不起  你现在还不能去看他
Unfortunately, you can't see him just yet.
需要等他情况稳定下来
We're gonna have to wait for him to stabilize.
还要多久
How long will that take?
这个不好说
I can't really say.
可能要几小时
Could be hours,
一旦可以探视  我们会立刻通知你
but we'll let you know just as soon as you could see him.
谢谢
Thank you.
要不要我们送你回家睡会儿
Um, maybe we should get you home for a couple hours?
休息一下
Get some rest?
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
我也不走
Me, neither.
你们有谁特别想刷牙的吗
Well, is anyone else dying to brush their teeth,
我想刷牙了
or is it just me?
我回家去拿些东西过来怎样
What if I ran over to the house and picked up a few things?
玛丽  我可以顺路去趟你家
Marie? I could swing by your place.
那太好了
That would be great.
谢谢  沃尔特
Thanks, Walt.
那好
Okay.
本德尔医生
Dr. Bender?
Dr. Bender.
沃尔特  沃尔特
Walt. Walt.
刚听说他挺过来了
We just heard he came through?
是的  情况算是...较为乐观吧
Yeah, well, it's, uh, you know, guardedly good news.
谢天谢地  这是好事
Thank God. I'll take it. Yeah.
各位  这是汉克的连襟  沃尔特
Hey, guys, this is Hank's brother-in-law, Walt.
你好
Hi.
-你好  -你好
- Hello. - Hi.
我们在讲汉克的故事
We were just swapping Hank stories.
是吗  那可...  够说一整天的
Oh, well, that could... that could go on all day.
天知道  他的故事太多了
God knows, there's a million of them.
这会儿...
Meanwhile...
该死的人渣
Miserable piece of shit.
开枪的杂种
Guy who shot him,
还活着  就在楼上
the one that's left, he's up there,
用着止疼药
got the painkillers going on,
舒舒服服地躺在那里
resting comfortably.
花的是纳税人的钱
Your tax dollars at work.
你该去看看汉克把那杂种弄成什么样了
You ought to see what Hank did to that bastard.
想看看吗
Want to see?
来吧  我带你去
Come on, let me show you.
可以吗
We can do this?
舒服吗  你个人渣
You comfortable, you piece of shit?
-抓住他了  -嗯
- You got him? - Yeah.
拉起来
Come on.
放松  放松
Easy, easy.
进去
Come on!
不爽
No.
给你一个  你...
One for you and you-- eh
你他妈终于来了
Finally. About damn time.
为什么没有制毒
Why isn't there anything cooking?
沃尔特·怀特  有你的电话
Walter White to the nearest courtesy phone.
-接线员  -我是沃尔特·怀特
- Operator. - This is Walter White.
我帮你接过去
I'll connect you.
我们有麻烦了  大麻烦
Yo, we got problems, big ones.
雷弗里德  感谢你的电话再次来电
Reverend, so nice of you to call...again.
快点开手机
Turn your phone on already.
我一定会查明情况的
You know, I will definitely look into that.
这样吧
I'll tell you what. Why don't I
我现在就用手机打给你
just call you right back on my cell phone.
好吗
Okay?
我叫你要等我
I told you to wait.
都不知道跟你说过多少遍了
I don't know how many more ways I could say it.
是啊  混球 我一直在等
Yeah, dick, I was waiting,
然后那个阴森恐怖的闷头男来了
and then that creepy, quiet guy showed up.
古斯来了
Gus came by?
不是他  老兄
Not him, man.
显然我还不配和他见面
Apparently I'm not worthy of meeting him.
是另外一个  我够资格和他讲话那个
It was the other one, the one that I'm qualified to speak to.
然后他开始问我问题
Then he started asking questions, too,
问我为什么还没开始制毒
like why I haven't cooked anything.
根据定额  我们明天该交货了
We have a quota. It's due tomorrow.
你是真不管  还是什么
Do you seriously not care, or what?
因为那家伙  他有双死神之眼
Because that guy, he's got, like, the dead eyes.
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
你记不记得我们和屠库在沙漠那次
Do you remember when we were out in the desert with Tuco?
你是说他用机枪顶着我的头那次
Oh, you mean when he put a machine gun to my head?
记得  有点小印象  怎么了
Yeah, I think that does ring a tiny bell. Why?
不是那个  他当时一直说
No. He kept-- He kept saying
在说  有人要
that-- that someone
从墨西哥来杀我们
was coming up from Mexico to get us.
你还记得吗  他说的是什么人
Do you remember? Now, who was that?
这和现在有什么鸟关系
What the hell has this even got to do with--
我记不清了  是...呃...
Look, I don't know. It was, um--
他的堂兄弟
His cousins.
是不是  杰西  他的堂兄弟
Right, Jesse? It was his cousins.
是  堂兄弟
Yeah, cousins.
管他是谁  老兄  怎么了
Whatever, man. Why?
有消息吗
Any news?
还是老样子
No change.
好的  那个  我...
Okay. Well, I--
我不知道哪把牙刷是谁的  所以我...
I didn't know whose toothbrushes were whose, so I--
我路上去了药房[兼售杂货]
I just stopped by the drugstore.
幸好有旅行装的  对吧
Thank god for travel sizes, right?
-谢谢  -没事
- Thank you. - Yeah.
我想去洗洗脸
Oh, I think I'm going to go wash my face.
不然我要疯了
I'm going crazy.
你去吗
Do you want to come?
好的
Yeah.
我买了糖
I got candy bars.
你是让我给你带这个吧
Is this what you were asking for?
对
Yeah.
我浏览了一下
Yeah, I-- I skimmed through it.
好像挺有意思
Looks interesting.
是的
Yeah.
汉克叔叔送我的
Uncle Hank gave it to me.
讲什么的
What's it about?
巴勃罗·埃斯科瓦尔
Pablo Escobar,
八十年代的大毒枭
this big drug guy in the '80s.
哦  我记得在新闻里看见过他
Yeah. Yeah, I remember seeing him on the news.
不过  这本书更多的是写那些调查他
Well, it's more about the guys who investigated him
想将他绳之以法的人
and tried to bring him down.
其中就有缉毒局的  你知道吗
Some of them were DEA, you know?
汉克叔叔说值得被世人所了解
Uncle Hank said that they were worth learning about,
大家都知道巴勃罗·埃斯科瓦尔
that everybody knows who Pablo Escobar is,
但没人知道那些抓住他的人
but nobody knows about the guys that brought him down.
我想我从未想过这些
I guess I never thought about it.
他说书里描写好人
He said that good guys
的笔墨永远没有坏人的多
never get ink like the bad guys do.
所以他给了我这本书
So he gave it to me.
觉得我应该读一读
Figured I'd read it.
我  我得去...
Uh, I-- I need to--
-一会儿就回来  好吗  -好
- I'll be right back, okay? - Ok.
不  我向你保证  我们很努力
No, I assure you. We are hard at work.
这一点绝对不用担心
Absolutely.
那么我可以期待着  明天按计划收到货了
So I can expect delivery by tomorrow as scheduled.
这个
Well, uh--
恐怕不行了
No. Unfortunately--
恐怕我们这周不能够
Unfortunately, we're not going to be able to
按计划完成了
keep our schedule this week.
但不是因为偷懒
But not for lack of trying.
有什么情况我需要知道吗
Is there something I should know?
和你说个大实话吧
Well, to be completely honest with you...
盖尔真的害惨了我们
Gale really screwed us up.
当然不是故意的
I mean, not on purpose, of course,
但是他  他拖了我们的后腿
but he just-- he set us way back,
到现在我们一直都在赶工
and we've been playing catch-up ever since.
还有  我不得不出去办点事
And I've had to be out running errands
好让我们达到预期目标
and trying to keep us on target.
有几样设备
Some of the equipment
校准出了差错  然后...
wasn't calibrated correctly and--
其实都是些无聊的技术问题
Well, it's just all very technical and boring,
但是请放心
but rest assured that--
我们会不遗余力地去做
that we will do whatever it takes.
我的全部精力都放在这上面
It has my total attention.
如有必要我们会周末加班
We'll cook through the weekend if necessary.
下周前我们会给你做好四百磅
We will have 400 pounds for you by next week.
说话算数吗
I have your word on that?
当然
You do.
我向你保证
You have my word on that.
谢谢你告知进展
Thank you for the update.
有消息了
Any news?
没  我只是在瞎转转
Nah, I'm just-- just wandering.
你那边怎么样
How's everybody doing?
还算好吧
Well, as well as can be expected.
我感觉  在那边
It's this not knowing
手足无措的等待消息 才是最煎熬的
that's the hardest part, I think.
查出这些家伙的来历了吗
Anything new on these guys?
他们是什么人  想要干什么
Who they are? What they wanted?
没有  还没有头绪
No, nothing yet,
不过会查清楚的
but we'll get it.
史蒂芬
Steve...
你认为还会再有杀手来吗
Do you think there could maybe be others?
伙计  不会有人来杀汉克了
Buddy, nobody's getting to Hank.
他们只有这一次机会  但他们没得逞
That was their one shot, and they blew it.
所以  不会了
So, no.
没可能了
No way.
上帝
Jesus.
我真想走进去
I'd love to walk in there
一枪射穿那混蛋的脑袋
and shoot that bastard right in the head.
我也是
Me, too.
说
Yeah.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
太棒了  我们马上下来
Great. We'll be right down.
吃的到了
Food's here.
你喜欢吃洛博罗炸鸡吗
Hey, you like Pollos Hermanos?
还行
Uh, on occasion, yeah.
那儿的老板是缉毒局的资助商之一
Owner's a big booster for the DEA.
他听说这事了
He heard what happened.
要带晚餐来给这里所有的警察
He's going to feed every cop in the building.
那真是太棒了
That's-- That's wonderful.
是啊  而且是他亲自送来的
Yeah, and apparently he's bringing it by personally.
很好吃  对吧
Good, huh?
没错
Delicious.
您真是太慷慨了  非常感谢
That's so generous of you. Thank you very much.
没错  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你们听到了吗
Guys, did you hear that?
福林先生要悬赏一万元
Mr. Fring is offering a $10,000 reward
给任何能够提供线索的人
on any information about the case.
是吗  真是太好了
Well, that's-- that's wonderful.
谢谢  福林先生
Wow. Thank you, Mr. Fring.
不客气
You're very welcome.
正是因为有像你丈夫这样的人
Men like your husband are the thin blue line
才使我们免受那些人渣的侵害
between us and these animals.
我希望我能做得更多
I only wish I could do more.
我们很感谢您的支持
Well, we do appreciate your support.
那笔赏金可以帮我们扭转局势
This reward could turn the tide here.
帮助很大
It'll really help.
本人再次对此次袭击深表遗憾
Again, I can't express how sorry I am.
碰巧  我和施拉德探员有过一面之缘
As it happens, I actually met Agent Schrader.
真的吗
Really?
几个月前  在募捐的时候
Our fun run, a couple months ago.
福林先生是我们的资助商之一
Mr. Fring was one of our sponsors.
我和你丈夫聊过几句
I talked for a few minutes with your husband.
并且他还提到了你  怀特先生
As a matter of fact, Mr. White, your name came up.
真的吗
Really? Huh.
没错  因为刚好有个为你筹款的收集罐
Yeah, there happened to be a collection jar out for you,
所以我大概了解了一下你的健康状况
and we spoke briefly about your health concerns.
我希望现在情况已经好转了
I hope that there's been good news.
没错  是的  情况好多了
Uh, yeah, things have improved, yes.
真是好消息
That's wonderful to hear.
很明显看得出他非常关心你
It was clear to me how deeply he cares for you.
好了  我想我该走了
Well, I've taken up enough of your time.
再次感谢您
Um... thank you again very much.
很高兴认识您
It was a great pleasure to meet you.
-谢谢  -谢谢你
- Thank you. - Yes, thank you.
-我送你出去  -不  不用麻烦了
- Let me walk you out. - Oh-- Oh, no, it's not necessary.
我忘了跟他道谢
You know, I didn't say thank you.
我去送他走
I'll walk him out.
马上回来
I'll be right back.
你好
Good to see you.
鸡肉好吃吗
Enjoying the chicken?
很好  很好
Good. Good
不用谢  我的荣幸
Oh, you're very welcome. My pleasure.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
-鸡肉不错吧  -没错
- It's good chicken, huh? - Yeah.
-那就好  -福林先生
- Good. - Mr. Fring.
-我能  -怀特先生
- May I-- - Mr. White.
我只想再次感谢你
I just wanted to thank you again.
别客气  我的荣幸
Oh, it's my pleasure.
我能  我能和你谈谈吗
Uh, may I-- may I speak with you?
一下就好
Just a moment?
你知道
You knew.
你知道我的连襟是缉毒局的人
You knew my brother-in-law was with the DEA.
我会调查所有和我合作的人
I investigate everyone with whom I do business.
这就叫做谨慎
What careful man wouldn't?
他对我们  对我们的工作来说
He is not a problem for us,
并不是问题
for our business.
你来这儿
Your being here is--
你来这儿是想传达什么信息吗
Is this some sort of message?
我是来支持我资助的团体的
I'm supporting my community.
我和你一样  也要掩藏身份
I hide in plain sight, same as you.
满意了吗
Are we done?
不  不  听我说
No-- No, listen, I--
我连襟遭到攻击的事
This attack on my brother-in-law--
我不明白
I don't-- I don't understand it.
我不明白是什么意思
I don't know what it means.
拜托了  如果你知道些什么
Please, if you have some knowledge
可以告诉我的话
that you could share with me.
我为我的家人感到担心
I fear for my family.
我保证他们会没事的
I'm sure they'll be fine.
我听说那个幸存的歹徒
I am told the assassin that survived
受了重伤
is gravely injured.
我想他可能也活不久了
It's doubtful he'll live.
好了  说谢谢然后和我握手
Now thank me and shake my hand.
谢谢你  感激不尽
Uh-- thank you. Thank you again.
别客气  怀特先生
You're quite welcome, Mr. White.
出什么事了
What's going on?
怎么了
What's happening?
开始按压胸部
Starting chest compressions.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
-一  二  三  -要心跳颤动器吗
- One, two, three-- - Defib?
没有理由  病人挺不住了
No reason. Patient isn't insistently.
继续按压胸部
Continuing chest compressions.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
给我一升生理盐水
Give me a liter of saline wide open.
没有脉搏
I can't get a pulse back.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
还是没有反应  一  二  三
Still nothing. One, two, three--
好了  停止按压
All right. Stopping compressions.
时间
Time.
八点四十三分
8:43.
死亡时间  晚上八点四十三分
Time of death. 20:43.
下地狱吧  你这个人渣
Burn in hell, you piece of shit.
你好  胡安
Yes? Juan?
我想你已经听到消息了
I assume you heard the news.
你的人死了  我听说了
Your man died. I heard.
很遗憾
It's unfortunate.
是啊  很遗憾
Yeah, "Unfortunate,"
而且我还被联邦探员包围了
and meanwhile I have Federales surrounding my house.
你知道我在想什么吗  古斯塔沃
You know what I think, Gustavo?
我觉得一切都是你搞的鬼
I think you're behind all this.
为什么是我  对我有什么好处
Why would I do this? How would it serve me?
这就是我想知道的
That's the part I'm trying to figure out.
也许你想只手遮天呢
Go off on your own, maybe.
你以为这会有用吗
Would you actually think that would work?
胡安  你听起来很紧张
Juan, you sound like you're under a lot of stress.
也许该等你头脑
Maybe you should call me back
清醒一点的时候  再打给我
when you're seeing things more clearly.
我够清醒了
I see things clear enough.
一个缉毒局的人中了枪  就惊动华盛顿方面了吗
One DEA gets shot. All of Washington starts barking.
还连带墨西哥联邦特区  搞出这么大声势
The D.F. Suddenly has to put on a big show,
让我和我的盟友[西]都寝食难安
and I wind up with Federas in my rose bushes.
但这只是暂时的
But just for a while.
很明显是政治斗争罢了
Appearances, politics.
你还在听吗  古斯塔沃
Are you still there, Gustavo?
嗯  我在
Yes, I'm here.
我会撑住的  我总能撑过去
I'll weather this. I always do.
我弟弟是警长
My brother's a police chief.
我会去疏通关系  让他们帮我逃过此劫
I got connections. They'll get me through.
并且我会找到证据
And when I get proof
让其他人都知道你干的好事
and the others find out what you've done,
到那时  我们再好好"聊聊"
maybe we come pay you a visit.
也许我们...
Maybe we can...
斯凯勒  醒醒
Skyler. Skyler.
醒醒  玛丽
Marie. Marie.
他怎么样了  给我们点好消息
Oh, how is he? Tell me something good.
病人情况已经稳定  你们可以去看他了
I think he's stable enough now for you to go see him briefly.
很抱歉  直系亲属才可以进去
I'm sorry, but I'm afraid it's immediate family only.
我们都是他的家人
We're all family.
我理解
I understand,
但我们有明确的规定  我们得...
but we have a certain protocol here that we need--
我们都是他的家人
We're all family.